salecycle.com 2018-06-27

# SaleCycle Privacy Policy | SaleCycle

## SaleCycle Website Privacy Notice.

SaleCycle Limited (“ **us** ”, or “ **we** ”) are the “data controller” in respect of your personal information. This privacy notice sets out the basis on which we will process any of your personal information we collect from you or third parties, or that you provide to us either through the SaleCycle website or when you contact us (e.g. via our customer service team). 

Please read the following carefully to understand our practices regarding your personal information and how it will be treated.

Please note that this Website Privacy Notice does **not** apply to any personal information which SaleCycle may collect and otherwise process as part of the service which SaleCycle provides to its clients. Please see the [**SaleCycle Service Privacy Notice**](https://www.salecycle.com/service-privacy-notice) for details regarding how we handle any such information.

#### 1\. HOW AND WHEN WE COLLECT PERSONAL INFORMATION ABOUT YOU 

We collect and process personal information when you **:**

  * visit our website (including when registering on our site, or filling in forms on our site, such as when you sign up for newsletters);
  * purchase any services from our website, for instance on [https://shop.salecycle.com/](https://shop.salecycle.com/)  
  * contact our customer service centres or request information from us in any other way;
  * participate in our customer satisfaction surveys or other market research; and
  * communicate with us via social networking websites, third party apps or similar technologies. 

We may also collect information about you from third party sources, such as from your use of other websites which we operate and from related third parties such as sub-contractors. 

We may collect information from publicly accessible sources such as various social media platforms.  The information we may collect are name, job title, contact details, job role, company name and location. 

#### 2\. WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU

We may collect and process the following personal information about you:

**Submitted Information**

We may collect and process the following personal information about you which you provide to us: 

  * contact details (such as your name, address, email address and telephone number);
  * password and other authentication information;
  * responses to any customer satisfaction surveys or market research (unless these are provided anonymously);
  * financial and credit card information; and
  * your marketing preferences.
  * Your online activity on our websites. 

**Additional information**

We will collect and store your purchase history with us. Also, if you contact us with a complaint or query, we may keep a record of any phone number used to call our customer service number as well as the correspondence and the period of time it took for us to deal with a query or any request you had. We may also record your levels of satisfaction with the services we have provided.

When you visit our website, we may also collect information from you automatically, for example using cookies and other similar technologies. A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we may set on your device. You can find more information about the individual cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them in our [**Cookie Policy**](https://www.salecycle.com/cookie-policy/). This type of information may include the following: 

  * information about your device, operating system and IP address;
  * your login information;
  * browser type and version;
  * information about your visit, including URL, clickstream (i.e. your journey to, through and from our site), length of visits to certain pages, and page interaction information.

#### 3\. PURPOSES FOR PROCESSING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION 

We may process your personal information for the following purposes:

  * to provide you with the information, products and services you have requested and send you marketing and advertising materials;
  * to authenticate your access to our website;
  * for system administration purposes and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;
  * to distinguish you from other users (for example to remember your log-in details);
  * to monitor your use of our website to improve the user experience and to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your device;
  * to provide customer support and ensure we provide a good level of customer service;
  * to tailor any marketing or advertising so that it is more relevant to you;
  * to notify you of any changes to our services;
  * to conduct marketing analysis to allow us to assess trends and the effectiveness of our advertising and marketing campaigns (including using your personal information to evaluate, analyse or predict certain personal aspects relating to you, such as your preferences, economic situation, interests, and/or location); for security and fraud prevention;
  * to ensure that our website and digital properties are safe and secure; and
  * to comply with applicable laws and regulations.

We may also match personal information that you provide to us directly with other information about you obtained from or held by third party sources (such as social media platforms). This may include your contact details, demographic data, your social media interactions, preferences, shopping habits, interests, geographic location and age or age range. We may use this personal information to tailor and show advertisements more relevant to you either on our website or on third party websites (including social media platforms). 

#### 4\. LEGAL BASIS FOR PROCESSING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION 

We will only process your personal information where we have a legal basis to do so. The legal basis will depend on the purposes for which we have collected and use your personal information. In almost every case the legal basis will be one of the following: 

  * When the processing is necessary to fulfil a contract that we have in place with you (or in order to take steps prior to entering into a contract with you); 
  * Where we have your consent to our use of your personal data;
  * When the processing is necessary for our legitimate interests, to ensure that our services are properly provided and to promote our services; or
  * Where we are subject to a legal obligation and need to use your personal information in order to comply with that obligation.

#### 5\. WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

The personal information that we collect may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (the **“EEA”** ), including countries, which have less strict, or no data protection laws, when compared to those in Europe. 

Whenever we transfer your information as described in the paragraph above, we will take steps which are reasonably necessary to ensure that adequate safeguards are in place to protect your personal information and to make sure it is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy notice. In these cases, we rely on approved data transfer mechanisms (such as the EU “Standard Contractual Clauses” and the EU-US “Privacy Shield”) to ensure your information is subject to adequate safeguards in the recipient country. 

#### 6\. HOW WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We take steps to ensure that the personal information that you provide is retained for only as long as it is necessary for the purpose for which it was collected. After this period it will be deleted or in some cases anonymised. For example, where you have made a purchase with us, we will keep a record of your purchase for the period necessary for invoicing, tax and warranty purposes. We may also keep a record of correspondence with you (for example if you have made a complaint) for as long as is necessary to protect us from a legal claim. 

Where we have collected the personal information based on your consent and we have no other lawful basis to continue with that processing, if you subsequently withdraw your consent then we will delete your personal information. However, please note that where you unsubscribe from our marketing communications, we will keep a record of your email address to ensure we do not send you marketing emails in future.

#### 7\. SECURITY AND PASSWORDS

You must keep your password and any other authentication information for our website confidential. If you know or suspect that anyone other than you knows your password or any other authentication information, you must promptly notify us using the contact details below.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your information transmitted during your use of our website.

#### 8\. DISCLOSING YOUR INFORMATION

We may share your personal information within our group of companies (i.e. our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006).

We may share your personal information with our suppliers, business partners and service providers, where they are helping us to market and advertise our services as well as providing our services to you. 

We may disclose your personal information to other third parties in the following cases:

  * for the purposes of research, evaluation, and analysis;
  * in the event that we sell any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal information to the prospective buyer of such business or assets
  * if we or substantially all of our assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal information held by us about our customers and visitors to our websites will be one of the transferred assets;
  *   * **if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal information in order to comply with any legal or regulatory obligation or request; or**
  * to protect the rights, property or safety of us or our users, or others, and in order to enforce or apply our terms and conditions (this includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction).

You have certain rights in relation to your personal information. These include: the right to object to the processing of your information for certain purposes, the right to access your personal information, and the ability to erase, restrict or receive a machine-readable copy of your personal information. We will handle any request to exercise your rights in accordance with applicable law and any relevant legal exemptions. If you wish to exercise any of these rights please contact us using the contact details below.

You may also have the right to complain to a data protection authority if you think we have processed your personal information in a manner which is unlawful or breaches your rights. If you have such concerns we request that you initially contact us (using the contact details below) so that we can investigate, and hopefully resolve, your concerns. 

Our website and other digital properties may, from time to time, contain links to and from third party websites and services such as our business partners and advertisers. If you follow a link to any of these websites and/or services, please note that they have their own privacy notices and we do not accept any responsibility or liability for them. Please check any such third party privacy notices before you submit any personal information to these websites or services.

#### 10\. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY NOTICE

We may change this privacy notice at any time. The new privacy notice will be displayed on our website. The date this privacy noticed was last updated appears at the bottom.

Questions and comments regarding this privacy notice should be sent to [privacy@salecycle.com](mailto:privacy@salecycle.com). 

Full company name: SaleCycle Limited

Registered Company Number: 07148309

Registered Office Address: Alexander House 1 Mandarin Road, Tyne And Wear, DH4 5RA

#### This Privacy Notice was last updated on 25th May 2018.
